<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>FINA4350 Student Blog 2024 - Blog Post</title><link href="https://buehlmaier.github.io/FINA4350-student-blog-2024-01/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://buehlmaier.github.io/FINA4350-student-blog-2024-01/feeds/blog-post.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://buehlmaier.github.io/FINA4350-student-blog-2024-01/</id><updated>2024-03-04T16:59:00+08:00</updated><entry><title>Setbacks from News Sentiment Analysis (by Group "NewPotential")</title><link href="https://buehlmaier.github.io/FINA4350-student-blog-2024-01/setbacks-from-news-sentiment-analysis-by-group-newpotential.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-03-04T16:59:00+08:00</published><updated>2024-03-04T16:59:00+08:00</updated><author><name>FINA4350 Students 2024</name></author><id>tag:buehlmaier.github.io,2024-03-04:/FINA4350-student-blog-2024-01/setbacks-from-news-sentiment-analysis-by-group-newpotential.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Authors: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thong Pei Cheng (Ocean) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jang Jungmin &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wong Nicole &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yao Yi Tung &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeung Cheuk Hin &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Introduction:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In today's rapidly evolving financial landscape, the fusion of technology and finance has become increasingly intertwined. As a diverse team with academic backgrounds in fintech and quantitative finance, coupled with varied working experiences ranging …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Authors: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thong Pei Cheng (Ocean) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jang Jungmin &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wong Nicole &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yao Yi Tung &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeung Cheuk Hin &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Introduction:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In today's rapidly evolving financial landscape, the fusion of technology and finance has become increasingly intertwined. As a diverse team with academic backgrounds in fintech and quantitative finance, coupled with varied working experiences ranging from tech roles to private banking, we are united by our shared belief in the profound applications of NLP in the financial industry.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To kickstart our project, we have chosen to analyse news articles and determine the sentiment surrounding the assets (e.g. stocks, bonds, commodities, etc) mentioned within them. By extracting sentiment from these articles, we aim to identify whether the mentioned assets are likely to experience positive or negative sentiment in the market. This approach will enable us to gain a deeper understanding of how news impacts market dynamics and potentially uncover valuable insights for investors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, we will document our learning journey, and describe how we have come to a consensus on exploring this topic. we will present our findings thus far, shedding light on the relationship between news sentiment and financial market performance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reflection&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we delve into our present proposal, it's important to look back and reflect on our past ideas that didn't quite make the cut. We initially brainstormed a few concepts, such as developing a chatbot or a ChatGPT tailored to the financial data of companies, predicting loan approval, and analyzing news to generate summaries. In the end, we gravitated towards analyzing news with a focus on sentiment (positive/negative), and whether it was name-based or asset-based. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, we entertained the idea of feeding a chatbot or ChatGPT with company annual reports. We envisioned a system where users could ask questions or search for keywords, akin to a Google search, and the chatbot would produce reliable answers. For example, in the realm of financial regulations, users could input legal terms, and the chatbot, powered by Python ChatterBot, would provide specific answers, much like a digital attorney. However, we eventually dropped this idea, taking into account that adopting a more recent and reliable than ChatGPT-2 would incur considerable expense. This led us to brainstorm another idea that could potentially make a more meaningful impact on people’s lives. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, after our first idea, we came close to initiating a project centered on loan approval prediction. The idea was to forecast the probability of loan approval based on customer data, such as credit score, income, employment type, and the purpose of the loan. This would potentially facilitate a smoother and quicker guidance for customers, sparing them the hassle of visiting banks and enduring lengthy procedures. However, the issue we encountered was, first, the difficulty in sourcing personal information, specifically variables like credit score and income. While we did consider having customers provide their personal information via a Google form or survey, after discussing with our professor, we concluded that we should reconceptualize and aim for a topic that encompasses finance more broadly. Apart from that, loan approval may heavily focus more on numerical data, such as the credit score of an individual or total asset value that an entity holds. Text analytics may play a less important role in decision making, which weakened the significance of final predicted result. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The closest idea to what we aim to achieve with everyday financial news was summarizing financial news articles on a daily basis driven by our group members' firsthand experience. Most of us had undergone the tedious process of manually summarizing news from 6 P.M. to 6 A.M. for morning updates during our internships.  Consequently, we thought that creating a tool to automate daily news updates could potentially alleviate the workload for interns in similar positions. However, we failed at fulfilling the element of finance in this news aggregator. So, these previous "failures" have informed and shaped our current direction: providing a quicker and better understanding to investors of diverse market trends by analyzing news with three different sentiments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why this project?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world of finance and investing is highly dynamic, with asset prices influenced by a multitude of factors, including market trends, economic indicators, and company-specific news. Staying informed about these factors is crucial for making informed investment decisions. However, the sheer volume and complexity of news articles and reports can make it challenging for investors to quickly and accurately gauge the sentiment surrounding particular assets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To address this challenge, the development of a news sentiment analysis tool specifically tailored to follow the trend of a certain asset offers significant value. Such a tool would leverage advanced natural language processing and machine learning techniques to automatically monitor and analyze news articles, press releases, and other relevant sources of information about the asset. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary motivation for creating this tool is to provide investors with real-time insights into the sentiment and market perception surrounding a specific asset mentioned in the news. By quantifying and analyzing the “positive”, “negative”, or “neutral” sentiment expressed in the news, investors can gain a better understanding of how the market is responding to various events and news releases related to the asset. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tool would enable investors to quickly identify trends, sentiment shifts, and potential market-moving events, empowering them to make more informed trading decisions. Additionally, it can help investors assess the impact of news sentiment on asset prices and uncover potential trading opportunities or risks. By automating the sentiment analysis process, this tool would also save investors valuable time and effort, freeing them to focus on other aspects of their investment strategies.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell, the creation of a news sentiment analysis tool specifically designed to follow the news of a particular asset holds immense value for investors. It offers the potential to enhance decision-making, improve timing, and provide a deeper understanding of market sentiment, ultimately aiding investors in achieving their financial objectives. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Kickstart with code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why not start with a little experiment, extracting a piece of news to understand the sentiment? Hence, the first step taken was web scrapping to collect textual data. Python modules like selenium to interact with chrome played an important role to locate our target article. Below is a sample of the applied program code: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# Setup for selenium &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="kn"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;selenium&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;webdriver&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class="kn"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;selenium.webdriver.common.by&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;By&lt;/span&gt; 

&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# Prep work for opening Chrome browser &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;chrome_options&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;webdriver&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;ChromeOptions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class="n"&gt;hrome_options&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;add_argument&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;--disable-notifications&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;  
&lt;span class="n"&gt;driver&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;webdriver&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Chrome&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;options&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;chrome_options&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; 

&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# head to webpage of sample article &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;driver&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;get&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2024/02/28/bitcoin-etfs-see-record-high-trading-volumes-as-retail-investors-jump-on-crypto-rally.html?&amp;amp;qsearchterm=bitcoin&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; 

&lt;span class="c1"&gt;# extract all textual content of the article to a variable &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;article_text&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;driver&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;find_elements&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;By&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;XPATH&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;//div[@class=&amp;#39;ArticleBody-articleBody&amp;#39;]/div[@class=&amp;#39;group&amp;#39;]&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class="n"&gt;plain_txt&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;text&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;i&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ow"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;article_text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;][&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, by utilising the nltk package, an overall sentiment score was calculated, with the value of: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="kn"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;nltk.sentiment.vader&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;SentimentIntensityAnalyzer&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;SIA&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="c1"&gt;# put &amp;quot;positive&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;neutral&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;negative&amp;quot; label to pieces of text &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;sia&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;SIA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="c1"&gt;# instantiate imported module &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nb"&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;sia&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;polarity_scores&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;plain_txt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;))&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Output: {'neg': 0.0, 'neu': 0.876, 'pos': 0.124, 'compound': 0.9799} &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The high neutral was out of our expectation as we were hoping to be able to identify the potential of a certain asset class after the machine read the news. Simply understanding the tone of news article will not be enough to generalise reliable advice. Hence, further actions should be taken while analysing the news, given that they tend to be objective and remain neutral. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Next Step&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is suspected that the machine didn’t understand financial content, as it only calculated the sentiment score by general tone of text. Referencing to a similar project conducted by the IMF (Puy, 2019), labels of “bullish” and “bearish” were used while financial-related positive and negative terms were sorted out. Therefore, more research will be conducted to formulate better code for sentiment analysis.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;References:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pound, J. (2024, February 28). Bitcoin ETFs see record-high trading volumes as retail investors jump on Crypto Rally. CNBC. &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/amp/2024/02/28/bitcoin-etfs-see-record-high-trading-volumes-as-retail-investors-jump-on-crypto-rally.html"&gt;https://www.cnbc.com/amp/2024/02/28/bitcoin-etfs-see-record-high-trading-volumes-as-retail-investors-jump-on-crypto-rally.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Puy, D. (2019, December 16). The power of text: How news sentiment influences financial markets. IMF. &lt;a href="https://www.imf.org/en/Blogs/Articles/2019/12/16/blog-the-power-of-text"&gt;https://www.imf.org/en/Blogs/Articles/2019/12/16/blog-the-power-of-text&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><category term="Blog Post"></category><category term="Group NewPotential"></category></entry></feed>